Balaji Sundaramoorthy

Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu, India



balajisundarmoorthy@gmail.com



+91-73732 25882



linkedin.com/in/balaji-sundaramoorthy-899a7a152



https://balajisundar13.github.io/ Balaji Portfolio.github.io/

Summary

Process-oriented Data Analyst with 4 years of experience with total 5 years of IT experience in a Product companies. Skilled in Data Analysis, SQL, Excel, Tableau, Pivot Charts, Athena, S3, MySQL, Reports Creation, Jira, Agile, Linux, Git, R, Data cleansing and Data Visualization with strong communication skills. Experienced in working with IoT sensors data and creating a Dashboards & Reports for clients and interacting with customers on regular basis to understanding the business objective. Earlier led a QA team for manual and automation testing.

Experience

F. Data Analyst

Freespace

Mar 2023 - Present (8 months)

Worked with IoT sensors datasets to understand clients data analysis objectives and translate data into deliverable actions supporting the impact on the workplace and client's future workplace design. Created Tableau Datasets, Dashboards and Reports on Monthly & QBR basis with client datasets to support client goals and understanding the meaningful insights & outcomes.

Writing a SQL query to extract only the pertinent data for a customer report by filtering out the raw IoT data. knowledgeable about S3 bucket, MySQL Workbench, AWS Athena, and PSQL. Done multiple Analysis with IoT raw datasets in Excel with help of Pivot Tables & Charts.



Success4. Inc

Jul 2019 - Mar 2023 (3 years 9 months)

As a Data/Business Analyst. I worked with Data & Statistics, Having a regular meetings with different clients to understand their demands. Delivered multiple Business Intelligence real time Dashboards, Successfully handled Data integrations(Jira, Salesforce, Zendesk, HubSpot etc.) of customers data.



Software Engineer

Decision Minds

Jan 2018 - Jun 2019 (1 year 6 months)

Worked with team to build a Customer Success Product from scratch. Experienced in HTML, CSS, Angular, PSQL build a multiple pages and reported 1000+ functionality and UI bugs during the testing phase.

Education



AVC College Of Engineering

Electrical and Electronics Engineering, Electrical and Electronics Engineering 2012 - 2016

Licenses & Certifications



Google Proffessional Data Analytics Certificate



AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner - Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Issued Oct 2020 - Expires Oct 2023

Skills

Tableau • Data Analysis • Business Analysis • Spreadsheets • SQL • Communication • Python (Programming Language) • Microsoft Excel • Pivot Tables • Amazon Web Services (AWS)